FELIPE MARIN-VASQUEZ

1 : 0412 058 336

: pipe.m.v@hotmail.com

: Melbourne, VIC

CAREER PROFILE

Proactive, diligent and meticulous Junior React Developer with ample knowledge of React JS and the entire software practice involved in the production of applications through this library. I have a passion for programming which I have demonstrated through years of self-study with commitment, initiative and desire to learn the different languages required to code applications.

Additionally, I have extensive and solid knowledge experience across a broad range of different software in a diverse range of industries such as: Retail, Foreign Exchange, Exporting, Outsourcing and Building companies. I possess proven ability to combine vision, decision-making and strong business acumen with well-developed project management and leadership qualities to support successful company operations.

Working effectively as a member of a team is important to me, in my previous positions I worked as an integral part of a team which together, worked towards common goals and targets. I have a proven track record working with projects in different industries and I am more than able to provide all my knowledge and enthusiasm to help support the team.

SKILLS

Key Skills

Debugging, Application Development, front-end Architecture, UI Designing, Coding, Project Management.

IT Support

I have extensive PC knowledge in diagnosing issues to determine causes and suggest solutions and have the ability to install and maintain hardware and software components and perform basic malware analysis and prevention.

Communication and Customer Service

My communication skills has been a great asset during my career. I have developed these skills acting as a mediator between the Worker's Union and the company in order to reach Labour Union Agreements. Additionally, my communications skills helped me significantly when working for Flight Centre where the goal was to reached great deals when trading foreign exchange currencies with a diverse range of clients.

SYSTEMS & APPLICATIONS

- HTML CSS SCSS Bootstrap JavaScript React JS Node.js SQL GitHub Webpack NPM •
- Proven knowledge of different Operating Systems and computer hardware.
- VsCode, Atom, Git, Github, ReactApp, Node and NPM package and Meta4 People Net system (ERP).
- High proficient user of Microsoft Office Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project, Outlook and Power BI.
- Used different communication tools like Slack, Zoom, Skype, Microsoft Team and Cisco Webex Meetings.
- High knowledge and ability use of various types of Accounting and Financial systems such as; MYOB, XERO TMX, MoneyGram, Flightdeck Portal, and other banking portals;

QUALIFICATIONS & CERTIFICATIONS

Course	Institute	Year Completed
React Development	General Assembly	2022
Postgraduate Diploma of Project Management	Pontifical Bolivarian University	2012
Bachelor of Accounting	University of Medellin (Recognised by CPA Australia)	2009
Telecommunications Technical Officer or Technologist	Metropolitan Technologist Institute (Certified by Engineers Australia)	2004

CAREER SUMMARY

Role	Name of organisation	Year - Year
Data Coordinator	PetStock Pty	2021 - 2021
Logistics / Delivery Planning Assistant	BoxCorporate Pty Ltd	2014 - 2018
Consultant	Travel money Oz - Flight Centre	2015 - 2016
Head of Accounting	Inversiones Ucrania & Plantaciones Churidó Ltd.	2002 - 2013
Engineering Solutions Analyst	Enlace Operativo S.A	2010 - 2011

RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

As a Data Coordinator for PETstock I was accountable for providing support with customised reports to supply Chain department to make purchases and acquisitions decisions for the company.

Responsibilities

- Ensure master data accuracy across PETstock ERP and Warehouse Management System.
- Validate master data provided by suppliers.
- Collaborate with the Merchandising team to clean legacy product data.
- Use historical data and insights to slot products for all PETstock distribution centres.
- Collaborate with stakeholders to create reports for PETstock's Supply Chain department.
- Use advanced analysis to create and improve existing processes.

Achievements

I was trusted to take care of company's data bases without supervision.

Head of Accounting

Ucrania Ltd. / Plantaciones Churido Ltd.

January 2002- March 2013

As Head of Accounting, I was accountable for the accounting and financial information in order to make the financial decisions for the company.

Responsibilities

- Structure and managed a project in order to redesign the payroll system for the company which involved the development of technology in order to achieve the project's target.
- Analysed and reviewed GST, tax and withholding declarations;
- Allocated staff and financial resources to ensure productivity of the company was kept at a high level;
- Completed all payroll duties for company salaries, benefits, social securities and any settlements etc;
- Managed and coordinated the financial resources of \$2.5 million dollars using banking portals and by relationships with senior banking managers;
- Prepared and submitted monthly and annual financial statements to company's CEO and government auditors;
- Modelled and projected the upcoming year's budget by comparing current budgets;
- Work in line with company procedures and government laws;
- Negotiated collective bargaining agreements between the company and the workers' union.

Achievements

- Reduced the clearance from fourteen days to between three to five days by encouraging, motivating and leading a change in the management systems by reviewing and assessing the then payroll system.
- Reached successful agreements and solutions with the workers' Union that avoided the workers to strike against the company which would have been harmful for the company's finances and the workers families.

Engineering Solutions Analyst

Enlace Operativo S.A.

September 2010 - February 2011

As Engineering Solutions Analyst, I was accountable for the software development and information management in order to ensure the technological development according to the client needs.

Responsibilities

- Created and conducted training programs for customers upon implementation of payroll systems;
- Developed and managed different accounting software and systems;
- Ensured a high level of customer satisfaction;
- Managed reports required by several customers for their analysis;
- Worked in accordance to company procedures and met deadlines for task activities and goals.

Achievements

Successfully design, setup and reconfigured payroll systems for multiple companies with more than 300 workers.